So, uh, Reeden, I know, um, people have
described you as the ultimate chess
piece. You can can play in the box, you
can cover tight ends, you can do a lot
of things, safety, nickel, hybrid. Um, a
lot of people also had you pegged to go
earlier in the draft. Do you think is is
that a reason why you think maybe you
didn't go as early, maybe teams didn't
really know how to use you, but you
know, a team like the Bills come in and
say, "No, no, we got a plan for you and
you know, we know exactly what you want
to do." Like, how do you account for
that?
>> Um, like I just I feel like whatever
teams grabbed their hand on me the
earliest, it was going to be the best
team that I'd be on. like the Bills. I
waited my time. It was all in God's
hands. It's all in God's hands. And he
if he wanted me to pick here, fifth
round 167 by the Bills and that was my
dream and that's my goal and I'mma take
it and I'mma that's all I need is a foot
in the door. So, I'm blessed to even get
in this moment.
>> What What are you most comfortable doing
as a football player,
>> playing football like I did a lot of
work with the Bills where they came and
worked me out as a safety and we did a
lot of safety drills and they see they
can really mold me into being a top
safety on their team. So, that's what we
going to push for.
>> I'm curious about that. Can you tell us
about your interactions, how far they
went back, kind of who you met with, and
what that pre-draft process was like
with the Bills specifically?
>> Yeah, so uh I did a workout with the
Bills with uh cuz their safeties coach,
Coach Dana, and it was great. We had
dinner before, we had we watched over
film for like an hour, talked ball. Um
then we went on on the field, did some
field work, and he loved everything and
I loved his vibe and energy and I can
tell that they're he's ready to compete
and win. So that's definitely an
organization I'm ready to be a part of.
>> Did you um I read did you return punts
as well in your college career? Yes,
sir. And
>> and and what's your experience doing
that? How comfortable are you doing it?
>> I'm very comfortable catching punts.
I've been catching punts since high
school. Uh punt return, kickoff return,
and I was out there I was started
catching punts in college my freshman
year. So, putting me out there in the
fire uh going to make a play on special
teams. That's just boost the win
percentages. So, if that's another role
they need me to play, then I'm willing
to do that as well.
>> Congratulations again. We'll see you up
here in Buffalo.
>> Thank you. Have a nice day.
>> Yep.
Jaylen Kilgore, Mookie Hawkins.
Congratulations, man.
>> I appreciate you. How you doing?
>> I'm good. I know that we had uh we spoke
at the combine about uh coming to
Buffalo. Now it's finally came to
fruition, but uh know what what did you
take about this process and how excited
were you when you got the call?
>> Uh it was the feelings was through the
roof, man. I waited my time and God said
this is the right time for me and he
rose on the third day and the day day
three was my day. So, I just I'm blessed
to be in this opportunity to have this
opportunity and be in this position cuz
where I'm from, all we need is a foot in
the door to show greatness. So,
>> where where do you feel that where you
can make the fastest impact on this
defense?
>> Um, I feel like it's wherever the
coaches fit me at the fastest. Like I I
was like I said, I was talking with
coach Dana. We was working out a lot at
safety. So, that's probably where
they're going to start me off at first.
And if that's where I need to be, then
that's where I'll play. But, if they
need to move it somewhere else and play,
um, I'm I'm willing to do that as well.
>> What would you uh call your play style?
What is what would you say what your
play style would be?
>> Um, I just say violent. I I attack the
ball violent. I tackle people violent.
Um, I get the people on the ground
violent. So, and I hustle to the ball
violently. So, that's what I would like
to say my defense what my style of
defense is.
>> All right. You're here in Buffalo now.
So, what would be your message to Bills
Mafia?
>> Uh, my message to Bills Mafia is let's
go win. Let's go win. Let's go. Let's
let's let's get through the playoffs and
let's go win big. So, I'm ready to do
that.
>> Congratulations, my guy. Talk to you.
appreciate you. Thank you.
>> Hey Jaylen, Katherine Fitzgerald from
the Buffalo News. Congratulations.
>> Hey, how are you doing?
>> What would um for you to reunite with TJ
Sanders? What will that mean?
>> Ah, that's gonna be that's gonna be big,
man. TJ was my dog. He took me up under
his wing my first year that I was here.
And like he always knew he always knew I
was a good player. Like he was like
always talk he always talked trash back
to each other just like jokingly and
stuff. So, it's going to be good to the
team back up with him again. Was he able
to tell you much about the Bills during
the draft process or what did you learn
about the team from him?
>> Uh, he was just telling us that the team
is really together. Like we win, they
come in, they they're detailed, very
detailed about what they do and they
they play ball players. So, I'm willing
to be a part of that.
>> Thanks.
>> Thank you.
>> Hey Jaylen, Matt Pino from Syracuse.com.
Congratulations.
>> Thank you. I appreciate you. How are
you?
>> I'm great. Um, I guess first just what's
this day been like for you? I'm sure
like this weekend overall for all of you
guys is just kind of just waiting. What
What did you kind of do to pass the time
and what was the day leading up to when
your name was called?
>> A lot of praying. A lot of praying and
just sit sit with my family just telling
them that whatever position you whatever
whoever calls that you're going to be in
the right position. God is waiting,
letting you wait. He's he's he's putting
you in the right position. Um he's up to
something cuz God always is up to
something in my life. So, I'm blessed to
have this opportunity and be on this
team. And uh God said he was going to
put me on a winning team and and this is
what this is where I'm at. This is where
I'm at. So, I'm ready to take that even
further.
>> Jim Leonard, when he took over as
defensive coordinator a couple months
ago, he talked about having an
aggressive attack oriented defense. And
I read about you that in your senior
year, you played multiple positions on
offense, you played on defense. You're
used to making plays with the ball. I
mean, is that something that they talk
to you about is coming in here and being
somebody that changes the game that way?
>> 100%. That's what I'm coming in to do.
Change the game, help us win, uh, mold
with the team, build character with the
build character with the guys. Sorry for
the hiccups, but uh,
>> yeah. And just just really mold with the
guys and really just be a game changer
and just get us over that hump.
>> Have you talked to TJ Sanders at all
today after you were picked? I
>> I haven't talked to him yet. I ain't had
a chance to, but I'm gonna call him
right after this.
>> Awesome. Congratulations.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay. Good afternoon.
Good afternoon, Jaylen. George Rney,
>> ch community newspaper. How you doing
this afternoon?
>> I'm doing good. How about you?
>> Well, doing well. Yes, indeed. My
question to you is, how does it
translate from playing in the
Southeastern Conference for for the past
three years? How does how do you think
that translates uh now coming into the
NFL where a lot of the players majority
of the better players come out of the
Southeastern Conference?
>> Yeah, I feel like it's molded me very
well. That's one of the main reasons why
I wanted to come to come to the SEC
because this is I feel like this is the
best type of ball, college ball, and
this the close thing to the league. So,
and I'm going play the best competition
and because my goal is always been make
it to the NFL no matter how I got there.
And so just being able to play in the
SEC and being effective and being a
starter for all three all three years, I
feel like it very is going to develop me
very well into going into the league.
>> All right. Thank you so much. Look
forward to seeing you at training camp.
>> Looking forward to it. Thank you.
>> Congrat.
>> Thank you.
>> Hey Jaylen, I forgot to ask you uh when
I was on before. Um did you know that um
your former South Carolina um one of
your coaches is here at the University
of Buffalo, Pete Lambo?
>> Yeah, Coach Limbo. Yep. Coach Limbo.
That's my dog. He's That's what I
started off at with special teams. Coach
Limbo, he the one who put me back there
at P return and he trusted me to do it.
So, hey, it's going to be it's going to
be fun to work with him again.
>> Yeah, that's cool. Um, you know, do have
you kept in contact with him? He's been
up here in Buffalo for a couple years
now since leaving South Carolina.
>> Yeah. Not not not much, but it's it's
been mutual. It's been mutual here and
there. It's
>> always been good vibes with Coach Limbo.
Like I He's very very detailed about
what he want special teams, and I'm all
with that. So,
>> all right. Cool. We'll have to reach out
and uh and get some intel on you from
him as well. Also, thanks.
>> Most definitely. Most definitely. Most
definitely. All right.
>> Appreciate you.